snowys.com.au 2019-03-15

# Privacy Policy | Snowys Outdoors

Thank you for visiting Snowys.com.au ("Site") operated by Snowys Outdoors Pty Ltd. We respect your privacy and want to protect your personal information. To learn more, please read this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use and (under certain conditions) disclose your personal information. This Privacy Policy also explains the steps we have taken to secure your personal information. Finally, this Privacy Policy explains your options regarding the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information. By visiting the Site directly or through another site, you accept the practices described in this Policy.

**Protecting Your Privacy**

At Snowys.com.au we're committed to providing you with a high level of customer service. This includes protecting and maintaining the privacy, accuracy and security of your personal information. We are bound by, and will abide by, the National Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act (Cth) 1988 ("Privacy Act"). This is in addition to our existing obligations under the Privacy Act.

**What personal information do we collect and hold?**

In the process of conducting our business, we are likely to collect personal information about you. The type of personal information we collect always includes your name, your residential address, email address, telephone/mobile numbers, credit card or debit card details and products and services we provide to you.

If you choose not to allow us to collect this personal information we may not be able to provide you with the products and services you require. For legal reasons this information may need to be held by us after your account has been finalised.

**How do we collect personal information?**

Snowys.com.au collects personal information directly from you when you submit it online at Snowys.com.au, by email, by fax, or by telephone.

**How we use Cookies**

At Snowys.com.au we use cookies, a small bit of text used by your browser to uniquely identify you to our web server. We use cookies to make sure that when you add something to your shopping bag it goes into your bag and not someone else's.

We also use cookies to track how many unique visitors we have daily as well as general buying trends within our site.

This information is only for Snowys.com.au internal use and will never be distributed to any other parties. The cookie is set to expire as soon as you quit your browser, but will accept the cookie again when you revisit our site.

**Rate and Review**

If you provide a review or rating for a product available through Snowys.com.au, we reserve the right to publish part or all of your review or rating, together with your first name and suburb and/or postcode.

**Links to Other Sites**

Snowys.com.au contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we, Snowys.com.au, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by Snowys.com.au.

**How do we use personal information?**

The primary use of the personal information we collect about you will be used solely for the purpose of processing your order and communicating with you about:

  * returns and exchange authorisations
  * emailing you tax invoices
  * delivery of the products you have purchased
  * dispatch and tracking information
  * providing you with the products and services you have asked for
  * sending you our newsletter or special offers
  * administering your account
  * maintaining our relationship with you.

You may also sign up to receive our periodic newsletter and special offer emails. In addition, after completing the checkout process, we reserve the right to include your e-mail address as part of our email communications. You may unsubscribe from any of our promotional emails if you choose by following the instructions in each promotional email. From time to time we will send order confirmation emails and other transactional emails. You may not unsubscribe from these types of transactional emails.

We may use your personal information for research and development of our products or to send you information about other products and services, which we provide, which may be of interest to you.

**Disclosure of personal information**

We may use or disclose your personal information to organisations outside Snowys.com.au and its related companies for purposes relating to the management of your account with us. Such organisations include:

  * service providers who manage some of the services we provide to you
  * mailing systems which organise delivery of the products you have purchased
  * maintenance and repair services
  * market research providers
  * our professional advisers (accountants and lawyers)

We require these organisations to adhere to strict confidentiality about your personal information and also seek to ensure that they adhere to the National Privacy Principles. These service providers may not use your personal information for their own marketing purposes.

**Security**

Snowys.com.au takes reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is secure. We have robust systems and procedures in place to protect your privacy whenever we collect, store, and use or disclose personal information. We are continually upgrading these systems and reviewing our procedures to ensure the highest standards of security is used to protect your personal information. As a condition of working at Snowys.com.au all our employees sign a confidentiality agreement.

Further, National Australia Bank's secure payment gateway encrypts your credit card details and processes in real time, instantly sending back details if they are approved. Sensitive credit card payment details are never stored on our website or within our internal database system.

**How to access and amend personal information**

You may update, correct, and delete your personal information by going to "My Account" on our site. In addition, on request from you we will provide details of the personal information we hold about you.

The release of information is subject to some exceptions such as information relating to existing or any anticipated legal proceedings, together with exceptions provided by the Privacy Act. Snowys.com.au reserves the right to charge a fee for providing access to your information.

To access your personal information, the request to Snowys.com.au must be in writing and can be sent by email t customerservice@snowys.com.au.

Our objective is to respond to any request within a reasonable timeframe and no later than 30 days.

We also aim to ensure that your personal information is accurate, up to date and complete. Amendment of your personal information will be conducted upon written request from you. You can contact our Privacy Officer by email at customerservice@snowys.com.au.

**Complaint lodgement and resolution**

Snowys.com.au is committed to the protection of your privacy and personal information. Complaints you may have about your personal information can be lodged with The Privacy Officer at: customerservice@snowys.com.au. We will attempt to resolve any complaint within 10 business days. If resolution is not possible within this timeframe we will contact you to discuss the matter further.

**How your information may be shared**

Except for the purposes outlined in the Snowys.com.au Privacy Policy, we will never sell or disclose your personal information; however we may release personal information under the following circumstances:

  1. when requested by the courts or laws (for example, a subpoena) or regulation or is requested by a government agency;
  2. where we deem a company or an individual may be engaged in fraudulent activity or other deceptive practices that a governmental agency should be made aware of; and/or to appropriate persons, where your communication suggests possible harm to others.

**Updates to this Privacy Policy**

If we change or update this Privacy Policy, we will post changes and updates on the Site so that you will always be aware of what information we collect, use and disclose. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time so you will know if the Privacy Policy has been changed or updated. If you have any questions about the Privacy Policy, please contact us at 1300 914 007 or email [service@snowys.com.au](mailto:service@snowys.com.au)
